SHAMIL IQBAL K B.Arch Architect



Address
Kodakkat House, P.O.
Pookkottur, Malappuram
Pincode: 676517
Kerala, India

DOB: 20/06/1993 Nationality: Indian Marital Status: Single

Contact (+91) 9633981434 mail@arshamil.com www.arshamil.com facebook.com/shamiliq Instagram.com/shamiliq

Portfolio Link: www.arshamil.com

Summary

A multitalented architect with interdisciplinary knowledge in Architecture, graphic design and product design with expertise in designing and executing architectural and interior projects. Profound knowledge in master planning, CAD/BIM, 3D visualisation, walk-through, graphic designing, web designing, video editing and animation.

Work Experience

INDIAN INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY (IIT) - MADRAS

Chennai, India

PROJECT ASSOCIATE Jul. 2018 - Jun. 2019

- Project Architect for the research facility International Centre for Clean Water (ICCW).
- Envisioned, designed and executed ICCW project.
- · Carried out research for the design of ICCW.
- Made presentations and walkthroughs for ICCW.
- Did the branding design and execution for ICCW.
- Organised various programmes at IIT Madras.

AUS ARCHITECTURE

Benagalore, India

DESIGN ARCHITECT Jul. 2016 - May. 2018

- Designed various projects in Residential, Commercial, Public building, Tourism, Healthcare and Hospitality Categories.
- · Giuded and mentored 4 teams of intern architects for 6 months each.
- Prepared presentations and drawings for various projects.
- Took up an entire project Government Model Higher Secondary School, Perinthalmanna, Malappuram, Kerala.

AMAR ARCHITECTURE AND DESIGNS (.and)

Chennai, India

INTERN ARCHITECT Jun. 2014 - Nov. 2014

- Took part in designing and execution of various commercial projects in Chennai.
- · Conducted photoshoots for many completed projects.

Pixels - Food Court for Forum Shantiniketan Mall

Projects

	May. 2016
International Centre for Clean Water (ICCW)	IIT Madras May. 2019
KPM Tripenta – 5 star hotel	AUS Architecture Jun. 2018
Weekend Cottegae - Chickmagaluru	AUS Architecture Nov. 2017
Samana Happiness – Super Speciality Hospital	AUS Architecture Jun. 2018

Gov. Model Higher Secondary School, Perinthalmanna AUS Architecture
Jun. 2018

Pazhassi Park, Wayanad AUS Architecture
Jun. 2018

Chamravattom River Side Beautification AUS Architecture

Jun. 2018

AUS Architecture

Education

T.K.M College of Engineering (University of Kerala) - Jun 2011 - Jun 2016

Kollam, Kerala, India

Bachelor's Degree in Architecture (B.Arch)

- · Secured a CGPA of 6.18 out of 10
- Secured GATE (2016) rank of 301 (All india General category)

Govt. Boys' Higher Secondary School - Apr. 2009 - Mar. 2011

Manjeri, Kerala, India

Higher Secondary Education

• Secured overall 83%.

Islahiya English Medium Higher Secondary School - Jun. 1998 - Mar. 2009

Malappuram, Kerala, India

Secondary Education

· Secured 95% in Tenth grade

Skills

OS Linux, Windows, Mac OS CAD Autodesk Autocad

CAD Autodesk Autocad

BIM Autodesk Revit Architecture, ArchiCAD

ModellingSketchup, Rhino 3DRenderingV-Ray, Keyshot, LumionWalkthroughLumion, Twinmotion

Graphic Design Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Corel Draw, Sketchbook Pro

VFX Adobe After Effects

Video Editing Adobe Premiere Pro, Final Cut Pro

Web Design HTML-5, CSS-3, JavaScript

Version Control GitHub, GitLab

Designing Autodesk Fusion 360, Autodesk Alias

Management MS-ProjectPresentation Powerpoint, Prezi

Languages English, Malayalam, Tamil, Hindi

Position Of Responsibility

- Organising team member, National level conference "Managing Water" conducted by IIT, UNESCO and Ministry of Drinking Water and Sanitation.
- · Coordinator North India Tour, Semester 9, TKM College of Engineering.'

Extracurricular Activity

Football

· Part of High school team.

National Scout and Guides

· Rajyapuraskar Winner.

Adventure Sports

- · Completed around 6 Trekks ranging from simple to difficult.
- Have tried Paragliding, Rafting, Rappelling, in various places in India